seek.co.nz 2013-05-25

# SEEK - Privacy Statement

##  SEEK's commitment to maintaining your privacy

SEEK's Privacy Statement has been created because we value our users and recognise their right to keep personal information private. This statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for all sites managed by SEEK.

##  Collecting information on SEEK visitors

SEEK collects information on our site visitors collectively including which sections of the site are most frequently visited, how often and for how long. This data is always used as aggregated, non-personal information. SEEK utilises this information to improve and enhance our services by monitoring the areas on the site which are most popular to you. This aggregated information may be shared with SEEK partners to provide them with an overview of how SEEK visitors use the site. This is done for the purposes of providing you with the best online career management services. 

###  IP Addresses

SEEK's web servers gather your IP address to assist with the diagnosis of problems or support issues with our services, and to monitor legitimate use of our site. 

###  Cookies & Applets

SEEK uses cookies to provide you with a better experience. These cookies and applets allow you to use specific services such as Job Mail (an alert service which emails your chosen jobs), Application Tracker (to manage your SEEK job applications), to remember who you are for Auto Login if you choose this option and to remember your last search criteria for My Last Search. 

Users who do not wish to have cookies active whilst they browse the Site can "opt out" by following the instructions on this [page](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ads/). However, doing so will prevent access to some areas of the Site and limit your use of some of the SEEK services.

###  Third Party Measurement

In order to better understand our users, SEEK utilises a third party measurement company, [Nielsen//NetRatings](http://www.nielsen-netratings.com/) to assess site traffic. A tracking code is used to collect the following information on the usage of the SEEK site:

  * The number of page views (or page impressions) that occur on SEEK;
  * The number of unique visitors to SEEK;
  * How long these unique visitors (on average) spend on SEEK when they do visit; and
  * Common entry and exit points into SEEK.

This aggregate, non-personal information is collated and provided to SEEK to assist in analysing the usage of the site. This data is also accessible by media organisations and research companies, for the purpose of conducting industry comparisons with other Internet websites.

##  Collecting information on SEEK Registered 'My Account' Members 

As part of registering with SEEK, we collect personal information about you in order for you to take full advantage of SEEK's services. To do this it may be necessary for you to provide additional information to SEEK as detailed below.

###  Registration

Registration is completely optional. However, registration for 'My Account' services allows you to take advantage of more of the tools and resources that assist you in finding a job. Registration includes submitting your email address. You may access this information at any time by clicking 'My Details' on 'My Account', or by clicking here.

###  Job Mail

Job Mail is an optional service. SEEK requests that you provide information relating to your employment preferences as well as your email address so that we may notify you via email of jobs specific to your needs. Users can modify or delete their Job Mail profiles at any time by going to the 'My Account' area of the site.

###  Storing your resume

SEEK registered members may elect to store up to 10 resumes in their 'My Account' area, and use those resumes when applying for a job. Deleting a resume from My Account will mean it is no longer accessible to the registered member. Please note that deleted records may still be stored by SEEK in testing or backup systems for a period of time.

###  SEEK Profile

SEEK provides registered members with the option of creating a personal profile. A profile includes your resume, employment and educational history, contact details, minimum salary expectation and the classifications and locations ('Profile') registered members would like to work in. Registered members' profiles can be seen by SEEK clients who place job ads in matching classifications and locations. Members can of course choose to hide their profile at any time. Registered members' Profiles will remain  anonymous until the SEEK client purchases access to a registered members resume and contact details. SEEK provides registered members with the following privacy options in relation to the access allowed to their Profile:

  * **Provide resume and contact details immediately**

When a SEEK client purchases a registered member’s Profile that resume and the contact details in that resume will be emailed immediately to the relevant SEEK client.

  * **Check with me before providing my resume and contact details**

When a SEEK client purchases a Profile, SEEK will send the relevant registered member an email with the job advertisement the SEEK client is considering the registered member for, and that registered member can decide whether to release their resume and contact details to that client or not.

  * **Hide or delete Profile**

Registered members can elect to hide their Profile, so SEEK clients cannot see Private Profile at all, whilst allowing the Profile to be stored in the My Account area of the site. Alternatively Registered Members can elect to delete their Profile. Deleting a Profile from the My Account area of the site will mean it is no longer accessible to the registered member. Please note that deleted Profiles may still be stored by SEEK in testing or backup systems for a period of time. 

All information provided when creating a Profile including name, resume, email address, telephone numbers, employment and educational history are used for the purposes of facilitating registered members job seeking efforts. 

Registered Members can modify, hide or delete their resume at any time by going to the 'My Account' area of the site.

SEEK reserves the right to disable or delete a Profile at their sole discretion. 

###  Online Applications

Making an online application to a job advertisement on SEEK is a free and optional service that does not require registration. Job applications require you to complete mandatory fields (first name, last name, phone and email) so that the advertiser can identify and contact you. Your application, including attachments and cover letters, are forwarded directly on to the third party advertiser and Registered users have the option of saving their resumes and cover letters. This information may also be disclosed to SEEK's service providers and contractors from time to time who assist us to deliver our products and services. 

SEEK may also retain this information in order to customise the service we provide to you. For example, SEEK may use this information to help create a SEEK Profile that you may choose to use in the future. We will not however activate this (or any other service) or disclose this information to any third party without your express consent. SEEK does however reserve the right to disable or delete a saved resume or cover letter at its discretion.

By applying to a position advertised on SEEK you are requesting that SEEK pass the information to the Advertiser as a part of your application. 

Additionally, you have the right to request your personal information direct from Advertisers on SEEK.

##  Email communications from SEEK

SEEK also provides you with selected information about job seeking and career-related topics in our email newsletter SEEK News Update. This free service is sent to registered users and provides the option of opting out of receiving these by changing your preferences in 'My Account'. SEEK may also make you aware of additional products and services which form part of your relationship with SEEK.

##  Storage & Security of Personal Information

SEEK takes all reasonable steps to ensure the security of our system. SEEK allows you to access your information at any time to keep it accurate and up to date. Any information which we hold for you is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities. 

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by SEEK. However, SEEK will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access of your personal information. 

You can also play an important role in keeping your personal information secure, by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used on the SEEK site. Please [notify us immediately](mailto:userhelp@seek.co.nz) if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.

##  Access to Your Information

As indicated in point 2, unless you become a registered 'My Account' user, SEEK does not collect information that identifies you personally. If however, you become a SEEK registered user, you are able to change, update or delete your registered profile at any time by logging in to My Account. You can also request your personal information directly from Advertisers who you have applied to on the site.

##  SEEK Partners & Advertisers

SEEK provides links and passes online application to third party sites. The use of your information by these third party sites is not within the control of SEEK and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of these companies. 

With the consent of SEEK's registered members, SEEK may provide that member's personal profile to SEEK clients who have placed job ads with matching classifications and locations to the registered member's profile and who have purchased access to the member's profile.. The use of that information by these SEEK clients is not within the control of SEEK and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of these clients. 

SEEK clients who place job ads on SEEK, and who purchase SEEK registered members' profiles are asked to comply with Australian federal privacy policy with regard to their own information handling practices.

You may also directly contact advertisers to request access to any personal information that you have sent as part of an application or as part of a profile.

##  Data Transfers

Sometimes, we transfer information to 3rd party contractors including persons outside Australia (e.g. a contractor located in the USA who provides us with services). By giving us your personal information, you consent to such disclosures. In addition, where we transfer information to persons outside Australia we believe that the recipients of such information are subject to a law, binding scheme or contract which effectively upholds principles for fair handling of the information that are substantially similar to the National Privacy Principles. 

##  Feedback

SEEK welcomes ideas and feedback about all aspects of the site. SEEK stores feedback that users send to us. This feedback will be used to administer and refine the service and may be shared with SEEK partners either in aggregate form or with specific identifying characteristics removed. 

##  Privacy & Site Changes

From time to time, SEEK may review and update its privacy statement. Revised versions will be updated on the website.

##  Contact Us

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with SEEK, you can contact us in the following ways: 

  1. Email: [ userhelp@seek.co.nz](mailto:userhelp@seek.co.nz)
  2. Telephone: +61 03 9510 7200
  3. Post: User Help Desk  
SEEK Limited  
Level 6  
541 St Kilda Road  
Melbourne VIC 3004  
Australia

##  More Information About Privacy

For more information about privacy issues in Australia and protecting your privacy, visit the [Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner's](http://www.privacy.gov.au/) website.
